# Jazlyn Hellman

Montreal, QC

#### Objective

A second-year master's student conducting research in the intersection of software engineering and human-computer interaction. I'm passionate about the role and impact technology, specifically machine learning, will have in society, especially on vulnerable populations, and how research in HCI can help inform future software to be more inclusive and ethical.

#### Education

#### M.SC. | 2022 | MCGILL UNIVERSITY | 4.0

Department of Computer Science; Funding: stipend from supervisor

# B.A. | 2020 | MCGILL UNIVERSITY

- Majors: Software Engineering, International Development w/ concentration in Int. Business
- Minors: Social Entrepreneurship, Arabic Language

#### Research Experience

- 2019 2021. Empirical evaluation on the current state of GitHub descriptions and using NLP and ML to automatically output understandable descriptions. Supervised by Prof. Jin L.C. Guo in collaboration with Prof. Christoph Truede. Empirical analysis, template creation and verification, text summarization and generation, administering and analyzing user study, writing and submitting the paper.
- 2020 2022. M.Sc. thesis in open-source software (OSS) usability and participatory design through frameworks of power and empowerment. Cosupervised by Prof. Jin L.C. Guo and Prof. Jinghui Cheng. Using methods such as open coding, grounded theory, interviews, quantitative analysis, NLP and sentiment analysis, design and systems development, usability testing. Mentoring undergraduate student.

#### **Skills & Abilities**

- Strong leadership and coord. ability
- Problem solving and critical analysis
- Collaborative team member
- Strong verbal communication
- Conflict resolution; social perception
- Strong public speaking and writing skills

#### **Relevant Courses:**

Software Engineering

- o HCI
- SE for Building Intelligent Systems
- O ML & NLP Methods for SE
- Mobile Privacy
- o Software Design
- Software Delivery
- o Database Systems

#### Business and Int'l Development

- Social Entrepreneurship & Innovation
- Fundamentals of Entrepreneurship & Management
- o Strategies for Sustainability
- International Bus. In Africa
- Global Issues on Devl'nt & Agriculture
- Computer Programming: Python, Node.js, Java, SQL, Scala, Bash
- Software libraries, tools, frameworks: Pandas, spaCy, NLTK, Numpy, MatPlotLib, Git, PyTorch, Maven, Ant, Docker, Puppet, AWS EC2 & Lambda Functions, Jenkins, Postman, Express.js
- Design/Usability Tools: Framer, Figma, Whimsical, Gimp, Adobe InDesign, Procreate, ATLAS.ti, LimeSurvey
- Operating Systems: Linux (Red Hat/CentOS), Windows 10
- Misc. Software: Latex, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, Anaconda, Jupyter, DB2, pg Admin, MS Office, Google Drive

## **Publications**

- Jazlyn Hellman, Jinghui Cheng, and Jin L.C. Guo. 2021.
  Facilitating Asynchronous
  Particpatory Design of Open
  Source Software: Bringing End
  Users into the Loop. Extended
  Abstracts of the 2021 CHI
  Conference on Human Factors in
  Computing Systems. Association
  for Computing Machinery, New
  York, NY, USA, Article 438, 1-7.
- (Preprint) Hellman, J., Jang, E., Treude, C., Huang, C., and Guo, J., "Generating GitHub Repository Descriptions: A Compairson of Manual and Automated Approaches" 2021. arXiv preprint.

# Conferences & Presentations

- SIGCHI 2021 LBW accepted and presented at LBW poster sessions.
- Vector Institute ML 2019 Conference – Attended and presented on behalf of CIFAR and Al4Good Lab.
- UCORE Symposium 2019 –
   Presented poster to McGill

   Faculty of Science on preliminary empirical evaluation of GitHub descriptions.
- ARIA Research Event 2019 Presented poster to McGill Faculty of Arts on preliminary empirical evaluation of GitHub descriptions.

## Languages

- English (Native)
- Hebrew (Conversational)
- Arabic (MSA; Higher Intermediate)
- French (Basic Conversational)

# Society Membership: IEEE, ACM, CSGS, PGSS Fellowships & Awards

## FELLOW, REWRITING THE CODE | 2020 - 2021

o A fellowship program for supporting and empowering women undergrad/master's students

#### FELLOW, AI4GOOD LAB | MILA INSTITUTE, MONTREAL, QC | MAY 2019 – JUNE 2019

- o Al.D. Chronic Pain Management System using Machine Learning; gained practical design experience (Whimsical and Figma) and ML experience (RNNs, LSTMs, Simulator); Project awarded the People's Choice Award
- o Representative at the Vector Institute's ML Conference in Toronto

## DISTINGUISHED LEADERSHIP AWARD | CJA | 2019

o Received on behalf of my student leadership of Am McGill and its impact on Montreal

# **Work Experience**

## TEACHING ASSISTANT | MCGILL UNIVERSITY, MONTREAL, QC | SEPTEMBER 2020 -**CURRENT**

o TA for COMP 202 (Introduction to Programming) & COMP 303 (Software Design)

## UNDERGRAD RESEARCH ASSISTANT | MCGILL UNIVERSITY, MONTREAL, QC | MAY 2019 - APRIL 2020

o Utilizing Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning techniques to solve software engineering issues in the Knowledge and Software Technology Lab, supervised by Prof. Jin Guo in collaboration with Prof. Christoph Truede.

#### BACK END DEVELOPER | COLOR KARMA, REMOTE | MAY 2020- SEPTEMBER 2020

o Translate business requirements into data and functional requirements to build process flow diagrams, ER diagrams, database, and APIs.

# ALUMNI NETWORK INTERN, AI4GOOD LAB | MONTREAL, QC | JANUARY 2020 - JUNE 2020

- o Conduct R&D on best practices to cultivate a strong Alumni community; implement solutions to foster a diverse and gender-equitable AI ecosystem
- o Organize events to foster community, including networking with Lab partners, technical workshops, and industry talks from experts

# IT AND OUTREACH COORDINATOR INTERN | FRIENDSHIP CIRCLE OF MONTREAL | JULY 2018 - AUG 2018

o Implemented and improved volunteer coordination system; helped with general technical problems; assisted with programming for children with special needs

#### ASHINAGA INTERN | ASHINAGA | TOKYO, JAPAN | MAY 2017 - SEP 2017

o Structured the Student Ambassador Program, Compiling leadership training manual, conducted leadership training

#### TUTOR | TEL AVIV & MONTREAL | 2015- 2017

o Primary and secondary school tutor and English teacher to vulnerable students and children of refugees.

#### Hobbies











# Leadership & Extracurricular

# **President**. CSGS 2021 - 2022

Recreate a vibrant CS graduate community post-Covid19 through social, academic, and professional events. Represent graduate students in department meetings and staff EDI committee.

#### Mentor . Al4Good 2020-2021

Alumni mentor for subsequent AI4Good cohorts. Mentoring teams on ML implementation, best design practices for unique ML applications, and general professional advice.

#### Mentor . Rewriting the Code 2020

Mentored an undergraduate SE student on matters related to educational and career choices.

#### Founder. Am McGill 2017-2020

Responsible for oversight & delegation of all operations: Marketing, long-term strategy, value creation, decision making, outreach to new members & networking with community organizations

# Student Ambassardor. Ashinaga. 2016-2018

Student ambassador and representative to head office in Tokyo, Japan. Established partnerships with other NGOs throughout Montreal, Responsible for organizing events, discussions, and volunteering for members.